[OP]
[OP]
Lyrics & Music by Jonathan Lee
詞曲 李宗盛
Arranged by Jonathan Lee
編曲 李宗盛
Performed by Jonathan Lee
演唱 李宗盛
Mojo Mojo Mojo Spy
Mojo Mojo Mojo Spy
Mojo Spy
Mojo Spy
Let's go
Let's go
This world's a flood of colors bright
這個世界五彩氾濫
Truth and lies blur our sight
真真假假迷惑我们的眼
Use your heart to see it right
用你的心认真去看
The answer's close, just out of sight
发现真相就在不远
Hey you good or bad, truth or lies
Hey you good or bad 真真假假
Can't escape this soul's disguise
逃不出这心灵的灰烟
Gather all your courage high
带上你的所有勇敢
Maybe you can save the sky
也许就能拯救这世间
Mojo Mojo Mojo Spy
Mojo Mojo Mojo Spy
Midnight kidnapping
深夜绑架
Hello? (Answering the phone here)
喂？（这里在接电话）
Ah, what?!
啊 什么！
Ring-a-ling~
叮铃铃~
What's that sound?
什么声音
What's going on?
是什么事
Time to get up!
起床啦
Why are you in my house so early?
你怎么一大早出现在我家
What was all that noise just now?
刚才什么声音那么吵啊
Huh? What's this?
嗯？这是什么
Hehe~ This is a gift for Locky!
嘿嘿~ 这是我送给奇乐天的礼物
It's called the Super Power Combo Alarm Clock!
名字叫超级威力组合闹钟
With this, Locky will never be late again!
有了它 奇乐天就再也不会迟到了
And in return...
作为回报
You have to treat Jingjing to three glasses of juice!
要请菁菁喝三杯果汁哦
Three glasses, three glasses!
三杯 三杯
You wake me up and still want a gift?
吵我睡觉 还敢要礼物
Hmph, so stingy!
哼 真小气
Oh, Jingjing...
对了 菁菁
Where's Uncle?
老舅在哪啊
Uncle left you a note.
老舅留了纸条给你
"Locky, I'm off on a small case.
乐天 我去办个小案
Rest well at home."
你在家好好休息
Uncle's working a case and didn't take me along?
老舅办案居然不叫我一起去
Locky, come play with me!
齐乐天 跟我一起玩吧
You big curly-head!
你个大头卷啊
I'm going to find Uncle!
我要去找老舅
So that's the gist of the case.
大致的案情就是这样了
Detective Chen,
陈侦探
do you have any thoughts?
你有没有什么看法呀
It does sound pretty strange.
听上去确实很奇怪
Uncle!!
老舅！！
Oh wow, I never expected
啊呀 真没想到
you guys to find your way here yourselves.
你们自己找到这里来了
Locky,
齐乐天
this was supposed to be a small case,
这本来是个小案子
so I didn't want to bother a big detective like you.
所以没想惊动你这位大侦探
No, no, no—
不不不
for a responsible detective,
对于一个负责任的侦探来说
there's no such thing as a big or small case.
案件是没有大小之分的
Excuse me.
请让一下
Who?
谁？
You again, you ghost-like guy.
又是你这个幽灵一样的家伙
Why are you always following me?
你一直跟着我到底要干什么
Sorry,
对不起
but I have no interest
我对你这种自称为侦探的儿童
in a kid who calls himself a detective.
并没有兴趣
What—
什么——
a k-kid?!
儿儿儿童？！
I'm Detective Hawxing, here to assist with the case.
我是来协助办案的侦探霍星
Please, tell me without any embellishment
请你们各位不加修饰地告诉我
the full details of the incident.
详细的案发经过
Mr. Niake.
尼亚克先生
They are
他们呢
the most outstanding young detectives in this city.
就是本城最杰出的少年侦探
Don't let their age fool you—
别看他们年纪小
they have a real knack for cracking cases.
对侦破案件却很有天赋
Sometimes they're even better than us adults.
有时甚至比我们成年人还要棒
Hello there.
你们好
Then let me go over the incident.
那么由我来说一下案发经过
Last night, when Mr. Nyack returned home,
昨晚尼亚克先生回家时
he saw an ambulance rescuing his mother, Ms. Taylor.
看到救护车正在抢救他母亲泰勒女士
That's how Mr. Nyack learned
尼亚克先生这才知道
that his mother's pet dog had been kidnapped.
母亲的宠物狗被人绑架了
His mother fainted from the shock.
母亲则由于受惊过度而昏倒
Then Mr. Nyack called the police.
接着尼亚克打电话报警
Since the pet dog wasn't a rare breed,
由于母亲的宠物小狗并不是什么珍稀品种
Mr. Nyack found it strange that someone would kidnap it.
所以尼亚克先生觉得有人绑架小狗很奇怪
So the suspect left no clues at all?
难道说疑犯就没有留下任何线索
There is a clue.
线索倒是有
The entire kidnapping
绑架的整个过程
was recorded in detail by surveillance cameras.
已经被监控录像详细地录制下来了
Here it comes.
来啦
Go, go, go!
加油 加油 加油
So he's Santa Claus.
原来他是圣诞老人
That's the crime footage.
犯罪的记录就是以上这些
Where was the kidnapper's last call made to?
绑架者最后那个电话是往哪里打的
The last call was made to the emergency center.
最后的电话是打给急救中心的
I know who the criminal is.
我知道罪犯是谁了
Then who is it?
那你说是谁
That fast, huh?
这么快就知道了
The suspect is Niak.
疑犯就是尼亚克
La la la~
啦啦啦
First, it's this late at night,
首先 这么晚了
but the old lady opened the door without any hesitation.
老奶奶开门一点都不迟疑
That means the person she saw must be someone she knows.
这说明来的人肯定不会是不认识的
Second, dogs usually bark and bite at strangers,
其次,狗狗如果看到陌生人一般会又咬又叫的
but this one didn't.
但他却没有如此
Clearly, he's very familiar with the criminal.
很显然,和罪犯很熟悉
Finally, the criminal even called an ambulance.
最后,罪犯还打了电话叫救护车
That shows he really cares about the old lady's safety.
这说明他很关心老奶奶的安危
All of this points to only one person: Mr. Niak is the criminal.
所有这一切都表明只有尼亚克先生是罪犯才解释得通
No, no, it's not me. How could it be?
不,不,不是我,怎么可能是我呢
No, it's not me, really not me. How could it be?
不,不是我,真的不是我,怎么可能
Your judgment is too hasty.
你的判断太草率了
Let me ask you: what's his motive? What reason does he have to steal his own mother's pet dog?
我问你,他的犯罪动机是什么?他有什么理由要抢走自己母亲的宠物狗?
What reason does he have to steal his own mother's pet dog?
他有什么理由要抢走自己母亲的宠物狗?
Then you tell me, why didn't the dog bark?
那你说说狗狗为什么不叫呢?
We're also puzzled about the dog's behavior.
小狗的问题我们也觉得奇怪
Pomeranians are usually easy to tease,
一般博美犬都很好逗
and they're known for barking a lot.
特点就是爱叫
But Mr. Niak said the Pomeranian he found was very special.
但是尼亚克先生说他找到的这只博美犬很特别
Gentle and doesn't bark.
温顺又不乱叫
So she gave it to her own mother.
所以就送给了自己的母亲。
So according to what Locky just said
那么照乐天刚才的说法
Snatching away the dog I gave to my own mother.
自己抢走自己送给母亲的狗
That doesn't hold up at all.
实在是不成立
Why did the old lady open the door so easily, then?
那为什么老奶奶这么轻易就开门了呢
That night,
因为当天晚上
Mr. Nyack is supposed to be here at 9:30.
尼亚克先生是要在九点半的时候
Visiting my mother.
去探望母亲的
So, Ms. Taylor...
所以泰勒女士
Thought he was his own son, so he let his guard down.
以为是自己的儿子就没有戒备
For the ambulance part—
对于救护车这一点
Guess this suspect still has some sympathy after all.
只能说这个疑犯还有些同情心
Special dog.
特别的狗
Some are special.
有些特别
Where have you been?
你去哪里了?
Peeing
尿尿
Drinking that much juice again.
再喝那么多果汁
I'm not bringing you along on cases anymore.
我以后就不带你来破案了
La la la la
啦啦啦啦
What've you got in your hand?
你手里拿了什么
This? Jingjing just found it.
这个呀 是菁菁刚刚发现的
Seems like it's about a cute little dog.
好像和可爱的狗狗有关
No more juice on the job, or you're off the case?
再喝那么多果汁破案就不带我来了？
Ms. Taylor, hello.
泰勒女士 您好
The First National Beautiful Dog Contest
全国首届美丽犬大赛
Cordially invites you to bring your beloved dog
隆重邀请您携带您的爱犬
To participate in the competition
前来参加比赛
This might be a clue
这也许是一个线索
I... I'm really worried about my mother
我 我很担心我的母亲
I need to go to the hospital to see her
我要去医院看她
Yeah, I think we should head to the hospital too
嗯 我觉得我们也得去医院
To check on Ms. Taylor's current condition
看看泰勒女士现在的状况
And once she wakes up
而且她一旦醒来
We might be able to learn
我们也许就可以了解到
More clues
更多的线索
How about we split into three teams?
不如我们就兵分三路
Officer Sima,
请司马警官
Please accompany Mr. Niake to the hospital
陪尼亚克先生一起去医院
Me, Locky, and Jingjing will check out the contest registration spot
我 乐天 菁菁就去比赛报名处了解一下情况
Hawxing will stay at Shuiyunli
霍星就守在水云里
In case the criminal calls
以免罪犯打电话过来
Sorry
对不起
I still need to investigate other clues my own way
我还要以我的方式查询其他线索
Hmph, such a goody-two-shoes
哼 假正经
【ED】
【ED】
That way, once we get there, we can ask around
这样我们去了之后也好打听哦
Its name is Little Kitten
它的名字叫小猫咪
Ah
啊
Look, tomorrow is waving to me from the horizon
看看明天 在地平线向我招手
Every day from sunrise to sunset, spinning into time's fantasy of lights
每天就在日升日落 转进时间幻想灯火
Waiting for each second, every moment of life
期待生命中 每秒每一刻
Bright eyes are sparkling, reflecting sunny smiles
明亮的眼睛在闪烁 映着阳光的笑容
He's at the bridge, at the silent crossroads
他在桥桥中在沉默着的路口